Now listen, yo!
People put your guns up
First I'll run dat
Run around and shoot them
Brand new sound, yes still survival
Here comes the sound boy, live in this world
Intelligence, strength, and luck are swirling, flow
My swelled mind is candid
One punch to Banner in Savannah
An easy knockout, bam bam bam
One time for your mind, live through this
Around the world
It haunts me, the pain of the past
Around the noble god are borrowed things
When the seed that's sown flowers, whose is it
Live and fire the arrow of faith, more more more
There is no peace where you're going
Come on, stand up, don't give up the fight
Now, yes, this instant, die die die
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
Kishimoto!
（計(けい)）岸本(きしもと)！
Thank you for everything.
（岸本）ありがとう 今まで…
Damn...
ああ… うぜえな　誰だよ？
Jeez... Who is it now?
あ… あの… やっぱり
Umm... I...
えっ？
（岸本）やっぱり行く所がなくて…
In the end,
I still don't have anywhere to go...
Oh yeah...
そっか 帰る所
なかったんだよな…
She doesn't have a home to go back to...
Kurono...
玄野(くろの)君 ごめん
I'm sorry.
No... It's okay.
（計）あっ… いいよ 別に
玄野君…
Kurono...
I Wanna Be There Now!
Mr. Prime Minister,
the government couldn't do anything
to deal with the situation
in the decade following collapse of
the bubble economy in the early 90's.
And not much has changed
going into the 21st century.
It is obvious that the earliest
economic policy has failed.
But now you're telling us that you've
developed a plan to overcome the situation.
Do you expect us to believe that?
You have to understand that reform
doesn't happen overnight.
We have been trying our best to...
If you keep up such a nonchalant attitude
ウッ…
（計）岸本…
the country will never be able to lift
itself out of this economic slump!
Kishi... moto...
the country will never be able to lift
itself out of this economic slump!
Yeah right, like that'd ever happen.
…なんてことには ならねえよな
（大臣）悠長とおっしゃるが
実際 株価は上がってきてる
Say what you will about my attitude,
but the fact is, stocks have been on the rise!
It's obvious we're making progress!
成果は上がってるんですよ
（評論家）それは 今後の推移を
見てみないと何とも言えませんね
I can't comment on that without seeing
how things develop in the future.
Let's say you're right.
But my point is it's all too late.
まあ 仮に そうであったにせよ…
Damn, she was so hot...
Let's say you're right.
But my point is it's all too late.
ちくしょう… かわいかった
かわいかったな　ちくしょう
Damn, she was so hot...
Have you looked at things outside Tokyo?
So hot. Shit...
（男性）そろそろ出るか？
（女性）そうだね
All right, shall we go now?
Okay.
I hope they still have tickets left.
（男性）まだチケットあるかな？
（女性）ねえ
なかったら お台場(だいば) 行かない？
If they don't, why don't we go to Odaiba?
（男性）ええっ？
（店員）ありがとうございました
Thank you.
Jeez, can't they clean up their own mess?
（店員）…たく 片づけてってよね
Excuse me...
（岸本）あの…
（店員）はい
Uh, yes?
Excuse me...
い… 今の 私の友達なんです
Those were my friends.
But there's one thing
that I want you to understand.
でも １つだけ分かってほしいの
I... I really do think that you're great.
私… 玄野君 すごいって思ってる
ホントに友達なんです
They... really were my friends.
Oh...
I'll take care of that in a little bit.
それ 私 あとで片づけておきます
Oh... Okay, thanks.
（店員）
そうですか？ じゃ お願いします
Huh?
（加藤(かとう)）映らねえな…
It's just not coming in...
（歩(あゆむ)）あれ？ あれ？
（リモコンの操作音）
This remote controller is broken.
兄ちゃん このリモコン 壊れてるよ
（加藤）あの中古屋のおやじ…
That old rat at the secondhand shop...
Don't worry, this is a bargain!
（店主）
大丈夫！ 絶対 買い得だって
You'll never find it at a lower price!
これだけ安いの めったにないよ
ホントかよ？
（たたく音）
Yeah, right.
おい…
（評論家）政府は何の対応も―
...in the decade following the collapse of
the bubble economy in the early 90's.
できなかったわけです
And not much has changed
going into the 21st century.
You got it! It's on!
And not much has changed
going into the 21st century.
やった！ 映った！
And not much has changed
going into the 21st century.
If you want to change channels,
And not much has changed
going into the 21st century.
（加藤）チャンネルとかは
テレビのほうでやってくれな
If you want to change channels,
It is obvious that the earliest
economic policy has failed.
You'll have to do it on the TV, all right?
It is obvious that the earliest
economic policy has failed.
Okay!
It is obvious that the earliest
economic policy has failed.
Okay!
But now you're telling us that you've
developed a plan to overcome the situation...
I don't ever want to go back to that room...
行きたくねえ　もう あの部屋には
（松村）玄野 帰り つきあわねえ？
Kurono, do you want to hang out after school?
はぁ？
（松村）日出台(ひのでだい)のＣＤ屋で―
They're having an autograph session
at a CD shop in Hinodedai.
サイン会があってさ
誰のよ？
（松村）いっぱい
Who's going to be there?
A whole bunch of people.
Supposedly lots of
magazine models are coming.
グラビアアイドル系大集合だって
It sounds like some publishing company's
doing it as a publicity event.
なんか
出版社のイベントみたいなんだけど
（計）いいよ 俺…
I think I'll pass.
（松村）
いいじゃん　行こうぜ なあ！
Aw, c'mon, man. Let's go!
Back off!
てめえ！
誰のおかげで そういうとこ
行けるようになったと思ってんだよ
Do you realize who you owe it to
for being able to go to things like that?
はぁ？
（計）カツアゲ食らってたの―
Remember who helped you back when
you were being blackmailed?
誰が助けたって言ってんだ！
１人で行け １人で
Go by yourself!
What are you so pissed off about?
（松村）なに怒ってんだよ？
KISHIMOTO
（計）ホントは俺とじゃなくて
あいつと住みたいんだろう？
You were asking because you wanted
to live with him, not me, right?
（岸本）
そんなこと言ってないじゃない
I didn't say that.
言ってるのも同然なんだよ！
都合よく利用しやがって
You might as well have!
You're just using me!
ふざけんじゃねえっつうの！
何だよ 俺は…
Give me a break!
What the hell am I doing with you anyway?
Why'd I even say such a thing?
なんで あんなこと… バカだ 俺
I'm so stupid...
岸本？
Kishimoto!
I'm here to read your gas meter.
（女性）ガスメーターの検針です
（北条(ほうじょう)）あっ…
What is she doing here? Damn...
なんで いるんだよ… チッ…
（女子学生Ａ）
ねえ ねえ あれ 北条政信(まさのぶ)だよね？
Hey, hey, that's Masanobu Hojo, isn't it?
Oh yeah.
（女子学生Ｂ）ホントだ
なんか 随分 昔のＣＭだよね これ
This is a commercial from way back, isn't it?
You don't see him lately, do you.
最近 見ないよね あの人
I think he left his agency or something.
I read it in a magazine somewhere.
（女子学生Ｂ）
事務所 辞めたとかって
雑誌に書いてあったよ
Really?
（女子学生Ａ）へえ…
もしかしてさ もう死んでたりして
Hey... Perhaps he's dead or something.
Where did that come from?
（女子学生Ｂ）
なんで そうなるわけ？
But it'd be funnier that way!
（女子学生Ａ）
そのほうが笑えるじゃん
Like, say he committed suicide
ホモの社長に迫られて自殺とかさ
after the agency's gay president
came on to him or something?
自殺なんかしてねえよ
I didn't commit suicide.
Oh, about the platform for Hinodedai...
日出台行きのホームなんですけども
（警笛）
ばばあ どけ！
Move, you old bag!
Hinodedai...
（女性）日出台の…
Shut up! Go find it yourself!
うるせえ！
自分で探せよ …んなもん
それが その…
（計）だから 何だよ？
Well actually...
What?
I was able to find it.
実は ホーム見つかりまして
Thank you so much for your help.
いろいろと
ありがとうございました
な… 何言ってるんだ？ こいつ
What is she talking about?
Since you told me to find it
on my own, I tried very hard.
あなたに“自分で探せ”と
言われたもので―
一生懸命 探したんです
おかげさまで見つかりまして…
あなたも どうぞ頑張って
And fortunately, I was able to find it.
I wish you good luck, too...
It's here!
来た！
I don't know what's going on, but it's back!
よく分かんねえけど また来た！
If I go back to the room,
I'll be able to see Kishimoto again...
あの部屋に行けば
また岸本に会える
くそ… そんなこと どうでもいいぜ
ああ 早く あの部屋に行きてえ！
Shit! I don't give a damn about
stuff like that anymore!
I want to go back to that room!
I wanna go there! Right now!
行きてえ！ 早く！
Ah, here it goes! Here we go...
来た！ 来た来た来た！
Such terrorist acts have been
going on for 5 days now.
（アナウンサー）こうしたテロは
今日で５日連続となります
被害者の大半はイラク人で
使用された…
The majority of victims are Iraqi,
and the bombs used in the attack are...
Kei, you're so cool!
（加藤）
計ちゃん まじカッコイイよ！
悟空(ごくう)とかケンシロウより
You're cooler than Goku or Kenshiro!
Who? Me?
（計）はぁ？ 俺が？
When did all this happen anyway...
一体 いつから こんなことに…
Ayumu... I'm sorry...
歩 すまん
絶対… 絶対 帰ってくるからな
I promise... I promise you I'll be back.
What the hell!
（北条）何だよ　予告だけしか
見れなかったじゃんかよ
All I got to see were the trailers!
あっ… もう！ こんな所で！
No, not here!
（トマオ）あっ また来たぜ
（計）あっ…
Here comes another one!
This one's a cos-player, huh?
（コンタ）今度はコスプレ野郎か
何だ？ こいつら
知った顔 １人もいねえぞ
Who the hell are they?
I don't know any of them!
Well then. You may ask me
anything you want to know.
（徳川(とくがわ)）
では 何なりと質問するがいい
I'll try to answer your questions
to the best of my abilities.
俺が分かる範囲で答えよう
Where are we? Whose house is this?
（コンタ）
どこッスか？ ここ誰ん家(ち)？
To put it simply, this is like a trial
you must pass before going to Heaven.
（徳川）分かりやすく言うと―
極楽浄土に往生する前の
試しの場所とでも言おうか
You call that simple?
（トマオ）“分かりやすく”って
分かりにきぃんだけど
I didn't understand
a damn thing you just said.
This is the place where it is determined
極楽に往生する者
無間地獄に落ちる者
who goes to Heaven and who
falls into the pits of Hell.
死者が集い
いずれかに振り分けられる場所だ
うん？ お前 漫画好きなのか？
I take it you're a manga fan?
いや 別に… すみません
Not really. Pardon me...
So are you saying that I'm dead, too?
ねえ 俺も死んじゃってるわけ？
死んだ感じしねえんだけど
I sure don't feel dead.
たった今
死んだ記憶があるだろう？
Surely you remember that you just died!
死を認めぬ者は
極楽への往生はできんぞ！
He who doesn't acknowledge his death
will not be able to go to Heaven!
この坊主 テレビで見たことあるぞ
死んだんだ？　ふ～ん…
I've seen this priest on TV before...
Guess he died.
Listen to him!
He thinks he knows it all.
それにしても
知ったかもいいとこだな こいつ
A girl? How unusual.
女だ　珍しいな
I guess Kishimoto isn't here yet...
まだ来てないのか 岸本は
Kato!
加藤
（加藤）あっ 計ちゃん
Oh, Kei...
岸本は
お前のほうがいいってさ …たく
Kishimoto said she likes you
more than me! Jeez...
So there are more.
なんだ まだ いるのか
質問 何でも受け付けるぞ
You can ask me anything you want to know!
（加藤）
はぁ？ 計ちゃん どうなってんだ？
Hey, Kei, what's going on here?
How would I know?
（計）さあ？ 分かんねえ
It's the fa...
You almost called me
a fag just now, didn't you?
今“ホモ”って言おうとしたな？
（加藤）いや 別に…
No, I didn't!
Shit. Quit following me around.
チッ… ついてくんなよ
Oh! Kishimoto!
（計）あっ 岸本！
Huh?
あれ？
（犬のほえる声）
ウワッ！
Whoa! Hey, stop it! Stop!
ちょ… や… やめて！
Easy there, boy!
（加藤）こら お前
You've been staying with Kei, right?
計ちゃんと一緒だったの？
（岸本）えっ？ ああ…
Um... well...
あ… あの…
（加藤）うん？
う… うん　一緒だった
Yeah, I was with him.
違うじゃん！
No you weren't!
Kato...
加藤君 私 私…
I... I...
（加藤）そ… そっか
ちょっと落ち着こう　なっ？
Okay. Try to calm down.
（岸本）うん… ありがとう
Okay... Thanks...
己の死をどう捉えてよいか
混乱しておるようだな
It looks like you aren't sure how to
deal with your own death. Am I right?
Huh?
Well, not exactly...
違うんですけど
You must pray to the Buddha!
念仏を唱えるのだ！
Just keep reciting Namu Amida Butsu!
“南無阿弥陀仏(なむあみだぶつ)”と
ひたすら唱えるがよい！
Those who recite the prayer
shall reach Heaven,
唱える者は極楽浄土に行き
唱えぬ者は無間地獄に落ちる
and those who don't go to Hell!
Hey, Kato.
加藤
（加藤）うん？
この間のゾク 来ねえな
（加藤）ああ そうだな
That biker's not here yet, huh?
No...
Maybe he's dead...
死んだかもな
（岸本）玄野君？
Kurono?
Hey, you!
あんた なんで そこまで
断言するか よく分かんねえけど
I don't know what makes you think
you're so sure about everything,
but chanting isn't
going to do a thing for you!
念仏なんか唱えてもムダだぜ
（徳川）なんだと？
What did you just say?
ここは極楽浄土とか関係ない場所だ
This place has nothing to do
with Heaven or Hell.
ここにいる人間は
まだ死んでいない
Nobody in this room is dead.
We're still alive!
生き続けているんだ　全員！
Every one of us!
I can't die now!
死ねないんだ　俺…
俺 まだ何もしてねえんだからさ
I... I haven't done anything yet!
I'm not ready to die!
まだ死ぬわけには いかねえんだ
（岸本）玄野君…
Kurono...
Kei...
計ちゃん…
Did something happen to him?
何かあったの？
No... nothing.
ううん 何も…
What's going on here?
（トマオ）どういうことよ？
Listen up!
いいか！ ここにいる全員―
All of us were assembled here to "hunt"!
ハンティングをするために
集められた
Every one of us is still alive but we won't
survive this unless we help each other!
今は全員 生きてるけど―
協力して やってかないと
生き残れない
Given the situation,
おかしくなっても しかたあるまい
こんな状況なら
I can understand why you've lost your mind...
（岸本）そうじゃないの！
（徳川）何はなくとも念仏だ！
No, you don't understand!
I don't care! Just pray to the Buddha!
Come on, all of you!
さあ 皆さん ご一緒に！
“南無阿弥陀仏”と！
Recite Namu Amida Butsu!
Namu Amida Butsu...
南無阿弥陀仏　南無阿弥陀仏
Namu Amida Butsu... Namu Amida Butsu...
Namu Amida Butsu...
（岡崎(おかざき)）南無阿弥陀仏
（徳川）南無阿弥陀仏
Namu Amida Butsu...
Namu Amida Butsu... Namu Amida Butsu...
南無阿弥陀仏　南無阿弥陀仏
Namu Amida Butsu...
Namu Amida Butsu... Namu Amida Butsu...
南無阿弥陀仏　南無阿弥陀仏
なんだか
変なことになっちゃってる
Things have gotten kind of weird around here...
Yeah...
Dumbasses...
アホか
（徳川）
南無阿弥陀仏　南無阿弥陀仏
南無阿弥陀仏…
I don't care anymore... Damn it!
もう どうでもいいや　くそ！
Is this a bathroom?
ここ トイレ？
（計）さ… さあ？
I... I don't know...
（宮藤(みやふじ)）南無阿弥陀仏… うん？
あの… やっぱり納得いかないんで
（徳川）何だ？
Excuse me... I'm still not convinced.
What?
It's just hard to believe this room
is a place one would go before Heaven.
（宮藤）ここがね
極楽に行く前の場所ってのがね
どうしても納得いかないんですよ
Look out there.
あれね
どう見たって東京タワーでしょう
That's Tokyo Tower. No question about it.
And this place is nothing
but an ordinary apartment.
この部屋も どっかの
マンションにしか見えないし
そう見えるだけだ！
It only appears that way!
でも
心臓の鼓動もあるし 呼吸も…
But I can still feel my heartbeat.
And I'm still breathing, aren't I?
ハァー…
これって幽霊に必要ですか？
A ghost wouldn't need to do this...
（徳川）生きているときの記憶が
そう感じさせているだけだろう
I'm sure the memories from when you still lived
are simply making you believe you must.
Are you... an otaku?
あなた オタク？
（計）はぁ？
Huh?
Well, do you like anime?
アニメ好き？
（計）別に
Not really.
Then why are you dressed like that?
じゃ なんで そんな格好してるの？
私 オタクとかに
あんま偏見ないんだよね
I don't have anything against otaku.
すっごい年の離れた兄貴がいてね
I have a brother who's a lot older than me.
And this is something I heard from one of
his friends, so I think it's probably true.
兄貴の友達から聞いた話だから
多分 そうだと思うんだけど
オタクっていう蔑称が
できるまでは―
He said people like you used to be
looked upon as more like heroes
そういう人って
ヒーローっぽかったんだって
back before "otaku"
became a derogatory term.
Huh?
（聖(せい)）70年代の
終わりくらいまでみたいなんだけど
I think it was like that
up until the end of the 70's...
兄貴
すんごい映画マニアだったんだ
My brother was a hardcore movie fan.
He told me he used to get a lot of
attention from girls because of that.
だけど
そのおかげで とってもモテたって
They used to look up to him because
he knew so much about movies.
“映画のことなら
何でも知ってるから―”
“尊敬された”って
いつから そういうの―
I wonder when people started
to make fun of guys like that.
バカにするように
なっちゃったんだろうね
Why would I know about what happened
such a long time ago?
（計）そんな昔のこと知るかよ
俺 オタクじゃねえから
I'm telling you I'm not an otaku.
Oh well, no big deal.
うん　別に いいんだけどね…
なんか フラれたみたいだからさ
It looked like you got
dumped by her so I was just...
What? Were you trying to cheer me up?
はぁ？
励まそうとかって… いいよ 別に
I'm alright.
Okay, if you say so.
そう… 別に いいけど
You're pissing me off!
（コンタ）うっぜえな こいつ
（トマオ）玉が歌うかよ！
There's no way this big 'ole ball
would start singing!
もうすぐ歌いだす
“ラジオ体操の歌”だ
I'm positive. It sings
an old radio calisthenics song.
Get out of here!
（トマオ）向こう行け
（ＪＪ）ゴー トゥ ヘル
Go to hell!
時々 こういうヤツ
電車とかに乗ってるよね
I see weirdos like this guy
on the train sometimes...
I'll kick your ass!
ぶん殴るぞ こら！
（徳川）放っておけ！
Leave him alone!
Your lives are now Over,
you bastards.
It's the beginning of a brand new day
Hey, Mr. Priest,
I'm sorry to tell you this,
It's the beginning of a brand new day
（加藤）
坊さん 悪いけど あんたよりは
次が どうなるか分かってるんだ
but I know more than you
about what's going to happen next.
It's the beginning of a brand new day
but I know more than you
about what's going to happen next.
A day filled with hope
（聖）なに？ あの歌
What's with that song?
A day filled with hope
Why are you here anyway?
なんで ここにいんの？
（聖）別に… なんとなく
Why are you here anyway?
Open your heart to happiness
No particular reason...
It looks kind of boring in that room.
Open your heart to happiness
あっちの部屋 つまんないし
It looks kind of boring in that room.
And look up at the big, blue sky
Listen to the voice on the radio
And your tears...
泣き顔…
（計）えっ？
Listen to the voice on the radio
ちょっと キュンと来ちゃったかも
They kind of touched me...
Listen to the voice on the radio
And fill your lungs
With the fragrant air
One! Two! Three! Let's go!
If something's bothering you,
just tell your big sister about it.
悩み事 相談に乗るよ
おねえさんに言ってみ？
Let me have...
させて
（聖）えっ？ なに？
Huh? What did you say?
...with you.
…クス …てよ
Let me have sex with you.
セックスさせてよ
What? Are you crazy?
はぁ？ あんたね バカじゃないの？
バカ…
Silly...
Okay...
いいよ
（計）えっ？
今 する？
Do you wanna do it now?
Your lives are now over,
you bastards.
What you do with
your new lives
is for me to decide.
So there you have it.
Your lives are now over,
you bastards.
What you do with
your new lives
is for me to decide.
So there you have it.
Huh?
（コンタ）ああ？ “新しい命を
どう使おうと私の勝手です”
Your lives are now over,
you bastards.
What you do with
your new lives
is for me to decide.
So there you have it.
"What you do with your new lives
is for me to decide.
So there you have it."
“…という理屈なわけです”
何だ？
What the hell is this?
New lives...
新しい命… “新しい命”って
What does it mean new lives?
"For me to decide"?
Are we gonna be USED?
（トマオ）“どう使おうと”って
使われんの？ 俺たち
（池(いけ)）
“私の勝手”って… “私”って？
"For me to decide"...
Who's ME?
No, not there...
（聖）違う… アア… そう そう
Yeah, right there.
It's going in. That's it...
入る…
（計）ウッ…
（聖）そこ…
Ferocious Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Grumpy Alien
Catch Phrase:
Ha!
（コンタ）
あばれんぼう星人？
Ferocious Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Grumpy Alien
Catch Phrase:
Ha!
"Ferocious Alien"?
Ferocious Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Grumpy Alien
Catch Phrase:
Ha!
I don't get it.
（トマオ）
意味 分かんねえ
I don't get it.
Grumpy Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Ferocious Alien
Catch Phrase:
Hmph!
I don't get it.
Grumpy Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Ferocious Alien
Catch Phrase:
Hmph!
Grumpy Alien
Traits:
Powerful
Big
Likes:
Tight places,
the Ferocious Alien
Catch Phrase:
Hmph!
What does it mean?
（宮藤）
何が言いたいんだ？
（トマオ）ふざけやがって
（池）将軍じゃねえのかよ！
This is bullshit, man!
I think you mean "Ferocious SHOGUN"!
The ball should open up any second,
（加藤）
そろそろ玉が開く　気をつけてくれ
so be careful.
Every time you say something's
going to happen, it does.
（宮藤）
全部 君の言ったとおりになる
What are you anyway?
何なんだ？ 君は
It's not just me.
（加藤）俺だけじゃない
こっち側にいる人間は―
All of us on this side of the room were here...
前から こっちにいたっつうか
来たことがあるんだ
Or rather, we've been here before.
Although we only know a little more
about the rules than you guys do.
この法則に関して
そっちより少し知ってる程度だけど
You should go change quick.
早く着替えてきたほうがいい
（岸本）うん…
Okay.
なんで 急に こんななってんだろう
こんなとこで
How did this happen all of a sudden...
and in a place like this?
死んでないよ
We're not dead.
でも 死んでんのに気持ちよかった
But it sure felt good even if I'm dead...
I said we're not dead.
死んでないって
Oh boy...
あらら…
（計）いいよ 別に
Ah, who cares.
We all start out as pure and innocent babes
Even if you taste the bitter fruit,
don't be discouraged, walk straight
I know it's in the past, but the rain still stings
I'm lonely as floating ice
I kiss your thin finger
And remember you crying
Even if this is the end
I won't forget your last kiss
I won't forget
I won't forget his kiss
（徳川）南無阿弥陀仏！
御仏(みほとけ)を破壊するなど もってのほか
Namu Amida Butsu!
Destroying Buddha?! Simply intolerable!
This place is neither the
present world nor the next world.
ここは現世にあらず
さりとて 来世にもあらず
何をしている？ 壊しては ならん！
What do you think you're doing?
You must not destroy it!
次回 “俺がやる！”
Next time: "I'll Do It!" Namu!
南無！